A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller, Sr. family photographs, Series 1003 FA447
Rockefeller Archive Center
John D. Rockefeller, Sr. family photographs, Series 1003
1840s-1937
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison) (1839-1937)
Strong, Bessie Rockefeller
Prentice, Alta Rockefeller
McCormick, Edith Rockefeller (1872-1932)
FA447
24.06 Cubic Feet 76 containers
Approximately 2,400 prints
Arrangement
Rockefeller family photographic holdings are arranged into the following series: Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001. William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002. John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003. William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004. John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005. Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006. John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007. Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008. Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009. David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: photographs.
Photographs
- John D. Rockefeller. Sr. family photographs, 1003; 24.06 Cubic Feet 76 containers
  Arrangement
  This series contains 4 subseries:
  1003A Bessie Rockefeller Strong. 1003B Alta Rockefeller Prentice family. 1003C Edith Rockefeller McCormick family. 1003D Edith Rockefeller McCormick family - Mathilde McCormick Oser.
  For ease of access, the material is further arranged by:
  Prints (Boxes P 1, P 2, P 3, etc.). Albums (Boxes A 1, A 2, A 3, etc.). Oversized (Boxes: O 1, O 2, O 3, C 1, C 2, C 3, etc.).
  - Prints, 1850s-1979; 15.2 Cubic Feet; Approximately 1,500 prints
    - Family Album 1, 1850s-1908; 35 prints (Box P 4)
    - Family Album 2, 30 prints (Box P 5)
    - Family Album 3, 1879-1919 (Box P 6)
      Scope and Contents
      Images 1-23 of 48.
    - Family Album 3, 1884-1905 (Box P 7)
      Images 24-48 of 48.
    - Family Album 4 (Box P 8)
      Images 1-30 of 98.
    - Family Album 4, 1863-1880 (Box P 9)
      Images 31-60 of 98.
    - Family Album 4 (Box P 10)
      Images 61-98 of 98.
    - Friends, 1892-1931; 13 prints (Box P 11)
    - Friends (Box P 163)
    - Group Portraits - Children, 1885-1931; 13 prints (Box P 11)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 1880-1933; 16 prints (Box P 11)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 1880-1933; 41 prints (Box P 12)
    - Group Portraits - Family and Friends (Box P 13)
    - Group Portraits - Friends - Mr. and Mrs. Alfred Eyears (Box P 157, Folder 2)
    - Homes (Box P 14)
    - Homes - Cleveland - Churches (Box P 14)
    - Homes - Cleveland - Euclid Avenue (Box P 14)
    - Homes - Cleveland - Forest Hill, 1917-1975; 51 prints (Box P 15)
    - Homes - Lakewood, NJ, 1909-1969; 46 prints (Box P 16)
    - Homes - New York City, 1858-1948; 43 prints (Box P 17)
    - Homes - Ormond Beach, FL, 1926-1946; 27 prints (Box P 18)
    - Laura Spelman Rockefeller, 1865-1900; 20 prints (Box P 18)
    - Laura Spelman Rockefeller, 1865-1910; 22 prints (Box P 19)
    - Pets, 2 prints (Box P 19)
    - Properties, 1979; 7 prints (Box P 19)
    - Properties - Lakeview Cemetery Burial Plot, 4 prints (Box P 19)
    - Relatives, 14 prints (Box P 20)
      Primarily unidentified relatives
    - Relatives - Spelman Family, 15 prints (Box P 20)
    - Toys, 1 prints (Box P 20)
    - JDR - Business (Box P 21)
    - JDR - Business - Associates (Box P 22)
    - JDR - Business - Associates - Ambrose McGregor, 1 print (Box P 157, Folder 3)
    - JDR - Business - Associates - Charles Pratt, 1 print (Box P 157, Folder 4)
    - JDR - Business - Offices - Cleveland (Box P 22)
    - JDR - Business - New York (Box P 23)
    - JDR - Business - Standard Oil - Stock Certificate, 1 print (Box P 157, Folder 5)
    - JDR - Busts (Box P 23)
    - JDR - Candids, 1921-1936; 28 prints (Box P 24)
    - JDR - Candids - Golfing, 1905-1933; 48 prints (Box P 25)
    - JDR - Candids - Golfing, 1905-1933; 41 prints (Box P 26)
    - JDR - Caricatures (Box P 27)
    - JDR - Caricatures, 1 print (Box P 157, Folder 6)
    - JDR - Christmas Cards, 17 prints (Box P 28)
    - JDR - Funerals - Wreaths, 24 prints (Box P 28)
    - JDR - Informals, 1923-1936; 37 prints (Box P 29)
    - JDR - Informals (Box P 30)
    - JDR - Informals, 1911-1936; 52 prints (Box P 31)
    - JDR - Informals, 1908-1936; 47 prints (Box P 32)
    - JDR - Informals (Box P 33)
    - JDR - Informals - Travel (Box P 33)
    - JDR - Informals - With Others (Box P 34)
    - JDR - Informals - With Others, 1910-1933; 40 prints (Box P 35)
    - JDR - Philanthropies, 2 prints (Box P 36)
    - JDR - Philanthropies - Associates, 1 print (Box P 36)
      William R. Harper, President, University of Chicago.
    - JDR - Philanthropies - General Education Board, 2 prints (Box P 36)
    - JDR - Philanthropies - Rockefeller Foundation, 2 prints (Box P 36)
      Obstetric Hospital Nurses Home
    - JDR - Philanthropies - Rockefeller University, 1908-1950; 39 prints (Box P 36)
    - JDR - Philanthropies - Rockefeller University, 1911-1939; 27 prints (Box P 37)
    - JDR - Philanthropies - Spelman College, 1883-1953; 31 prints (Box P 37)
    - JDR - Philanthropies - University of Chicago (Box P 38)
    - JDR - Portraits (Box P 38)
    - JDR - Portraits, 1850s-1930s; 36 prints (Box P 39)
    - JDR - Portraits, 2 prints (Box P 157, Folder 7)
    - JDR - Portraits, 8 prints (Box P 157, Folder 8)
    - JDR - Portraits - Sargeant, 2 prints (Box P 157, Folder 9)
    - JDR - Portraits (Box P 163)
    - JDR - Schools, 5 prints (Box P 40)
    - JDR - Tarrrytown Historical Society (Neighbor John Room), 1939; 12 prints (Box P 40)
  - Albums, 1890-1940; 3 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate; Approximately 500 prints
    - JDR and Laura Spelman Rockefeller - Portraits - Edmundson Portraits, 1904-1911; 21 prints (Box A 10)
    - Homes - Cleveland - "Forest Hill" (Box A 1)
    - Homes - Cleveland - Forest Hill (Housing Development), 1937; 14 prints (Box A 5)
    - Homes - "Lakewood, NJ", Clark T. Chambers, Real Estate, NY, 1940; 12 prints (Box A 6)
    - Homes - New York City - "Bedroom and Boudoir from 4 West 54th Street after installation in the Museum of the City of New York", 1938; 8 prints (Box A 7)
    - Homes - New York City - "4 West 54th Street", 1937; 29 prints (Box A 9)
      NAR copy.
    - Homes - Ormond Beach, FL - "Casements", 1937 June; 32 prints (Box A 8)
    - "Scrapbook of envelopes addressed to JDR Sr and JDR Jr." (Box A 4)
    - Travel - "Trip to Europe on a German Liner", 1890; 164 prints (Box A 2)
    - Travel - "Trip to Europe", 1900; 147 prints (Box A 3)
  - Oversized, 1865-1939; 6.6 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate; Approximately 320 prints.
    - Group Portraits - Family, 1896-1931; 9 prints (Box O 1)
    - Group Portraits - Family (Box O 9)
    - Group Portraits - Family (Box C 6)
    - Group Portraits - Family and Friends, 1899; 2 prints (Box O 1)
    - Group Portraits - Family and Friends (Box O 9)
    - Homes, 10 prints (Box O 2)
      Homes in Cleveland, New York and Ormond Beach, FL.
    - Homes - Cleveland - Euclid Avenue (Box O 10)
    - Homes - Cleveland - Forest Hill (Box O 8)
    - Homes - Cleveland - Forest Hill (Box O 10)
    - Homes - New York City (Box O 10)
    - Homes - New York City - 4 West 54th Street (Box C 6)
    - Homes - Ormond Beach, FL - The Casements, 16 prints, some color (Box O 7)
    - Laura Spelman Rockefeller, 20 prints (Box O 15)
    - JDR - Business - Associates (Box O 11)
    - JDR - Business - Offices, 1865-1894; 4 prints (Box O 3)
      Offices in Cleveland and New York.
    - JDR - Business - Offices - Cleveland (Box O 11)
    - JDR - Business - Offices - New York (Box O 11)
    - JDR - Busts, 1924; 13 prints (Box O 4)
    - JDR - Busts, 1920s; 10 prints (Box O 5)
    - JDR - Paintings, 13 prints (Box O 5)
    - JDR - Candids - Golfing, 1905-1920s; 4 prints (Box O 6)
    - JDR - Informals, 1930s; 3 prints (Box O 6)
    - JDR - Philanthropies (Box O 9)
    - JDR - Portraits, Approximately 30 prints (Box O 14)
    - JDR - Portraits, 17 prints with duplicates (Box O 16)
    - JDR - Portraits (Box C 6)
    - JDR - Portraits - Edmundson, 13 prints (Box O 17)
    - JDR - Portraits - Engelbrecht and Daguerreotype Facsimilies, 40 prints with duplicates (Box O 18)
    - JDR - Portraits - Engelbrecht at Ormond Beach, FL, 1935; 15 prints (Box O 19)
    - JDR - Portraits - Engelbrecht at Ormond Beach, FL, 1935; 9 prints (Box O 20)
    - JDR - Portraits - Edmundson, 1905; 15 prints (Box O 12)
    - JDR - Portraits - Timothy Cole Woodcut, 1900-1910; 22 prints (Box O 13)
    - JDR - Portraits, 1884; 1 print (Box O 13)
    - JDR's 150th Birthday Exhibit (Box C 1)
    - Francis Boland Dime (Box C 2)
  - Bessie Rockefeller Strong, 1003A; 10 prints
    - Prints
      - Bessie Rockefeller Strong, 10 prints (Box P 40)
  - Alta Rockefeller Prentice family, 1003B; 21 prints
    - Prints
      - Alta Rockefeller Prentice family, 19 prints (Box P 41)
        Portraits, group portraits, homes
    - Oversized
      - Alta Rockefeller Prentice family, 1896; 2 prints (Box O 21)
      - Alta Rockefeller Prentice - Wedding, 1901; 2 oversized prints (Box 1)
  - Edith Rockefeller McCormick family, 1003C; 18 prints
    - Prints
      - Edith Rockefeller McCormick family, 18 prints (Box P 41)
        Individual portraits and group portraits
  - Edith Rockefeller McCormick family - Mathilde McCormick Oser, 1918-1929; 1003D; 43 prints
    - Prints
      - Mathilde McCormick Oser, 1918-1929; 43 prints (Box P 42)